Inventory of the Nigerian Pamphlets and Other Publications Collected by Simon Ottenberg
Hoover Institution Library
- History, culture, language, 1904-1967, undated (bulk 1940-1965). (Reel 7-12, 16)
  - Ogbalu, F. Chidozie. Okowa-Okwu. Igbo-English - English-Igbo Dictionary. University Publishing Company., 1962 (Reel 11)
  - Ogbalu, F. Chidozie. Omenala Igbo (The Book of Igbo Custom). African Literature Bureau, Varsity Bookshop, Onitsha. 2nd edition., 1960 (Reel 11)
  - Ogbalu, F. Chidozie. Onitsha Province Rhymes. Shamara. Varsity Publishing Company, Onitsha., 1955 (Reel 11)
  - Ogbalu, F. Chidozie. School Certificate Igbo. African Literature Bureau, Varsity Bookshops, Onitsha, revised and enlarged edition., undated (Reel 11)
  - Ogbalu, F. Chidozie. Teach Yourself the All Accepted Igbo Orthography (The Vowel Harmony System). Varsity Publishing Company, Onitsha., undated (Reel 11)
  - Ogbalu, F. Chidozie. Western Igbo Rhymes. Nda. Varsity Publishing Company, Onitsha., undated (Reel 11)
  - Ogbalu, F. Chidozie. Why Do Candidates Fail Igbo in Exams? Varsity Bookshop, Onitsha., undated (Reel 11)
  - Okala, J.B.C. Etuka Bilingualism in Eastern Region of Nigeria. Eastern Nigeria Printing Corporation, Enugu., undated (Reel 11)
  - Okediadi, Eunice Chukuedo. A Short Biography of the Late Bishop Alphonso Chukuma Onyeabo, O.B.E. C.M.S. Niger Press, Port Harcourt., 1956 (Reel 11)
  - Okonkwo, M.N. A Complete Course in Igbo Grammar for School Certificate and Allied Examinations (New Authography). Zik Interprises Ltd. Enugu., 1957 (Reel 11)
  - Okoro, Nwakamma. The Ascertainment of Customary Laws in Southern Nigeria. Etudo Limited, Onitsha., 1966 (Reel 11)
  - Okoroh, Patrick D. A Short History of Uratta. Benson Press, Ijebu-Ode., undated (Reel 11)
  - Omo-Ananigie, Peter Inahoureme. A Brief History of Etsakor. Ope Ife Press, Lagos., 1946 (Reel 11)
  - Omoneukanrin, C.O. Itsekiri Law and Custom. Ife-Olu Printing Works, Lagos., 1942 (Reel 11)
  - Onuchukwu, W.I. English Ibo Phrase Book and Vocabulary. N.P.P. Press, Port Harcourt., undated (Reel 11)
  - Onuorah. (First Ibo National Monthly Magazine). Varsity Publishing Company. Vol. 1, No. 2., March1956 (Reel 11)
  - Opara, E.O. Ilu Okwu Igbo. Silent Prayer Home Press, Aba., 1950 (Reel 11)
  - Orakwue, Jerry I. Onitsha Custom of Title-Taking. Renascent Africa Press, Onitsha., 1953 (Reel 11)
  - Orisadipe, Ajidasile. Prospectus of Nigeria Art Centre. Olugbadewa Press, Lagos., undated (Reel 11)
  - Owonaro, S.K. The History of Ijo (Ijaw) and Her Neighboring Tribes in Nigeria. Nigeria Printing Works, Lagos., 1949 (Reel 11)
  - Owuteaka, Jere Ogo. The C.M.S. Niger Mission Centenary, 1857-1957. Mbidokwu Press, Onitsha. (Reel 11)
  - Plummer, G. The Ibo Cookery Book., undated (Reel 16)
  - The Presbyterian Church of Nigeria. ITU, Leper Colony. Founded 1923. Cooperative Farm Project. Founded 1966., undated (Reel 16)
  - Ozigbo, Mallam Emman. Traders’ and Travellers’ Companion. Hausa-English-Ibo. Goodwill Press, Port Harcourt., undated (Reel 11)
  - Roseveare, Margaret P. High Spring. The Story of Iyi Enu Hospital. Church Missionary Society, London., 1946 (Reel 11)
  - [Rowling, C.W.] Notes on Land Tenure in the Benin, Kukuruku, Ishan and Asaba Division of Benin Province. Government Printer, Lagos., 1948 (Reel 11)
  - Rowling, C.W. Land Tenure in Ijebu Province. Government Printer, Western Region, Ibadan., 1956 (Reel 12)
  - Shaw, Thurstan. Archaeology and Nigeria, An expanded version of An Inaugural Lecture delivered at the University of Ibadan on 29 November 1963. Ibadan University Press., undated (Reel 16)
  - Smith, S.R. “Markets and Marketing in Nigeria,” The Empire Cotton Growing Review. Vol. 6 No. 4 pg 1-11., 1929 (Reel 12)
  - Smith, S.R. “Bush Paths and Roads in Nigeria.” The Empire Cotton Growing Review. Vol. 8 No. 3 pg. 1-7., 1931 (Reel 12)
  - Smith, S.R. Smith, Sidney R. ""Notes on Clothing, Cloth and Cotton in the Lower Niger,"" The Empire Cotton Growing Review. Vol. 5 No. 2 pgs. 1-12., 1928 (Reel 12)
  - Society of African Missions [Societas Missionum ad Afros, Irish Province]. One Hundred Years of Missionary Achievement, 1856-1956. African Missions, Cork Ireland., undated (Reel 12)
  - Sowande, Fela. Ifa. Forward Press, Yaba., undated (Reel 12)
  - Spencer, J. A First Grammar of the Ibo Language. Sheldon Press, London. 2nd edition., 1927 (Reel 12)
  - Thomas, Isaac B. Life History of Herbert Macaulay, C.E., n.p. 3rd edition., undated (Reel 12)
  - Uka, Dr. N. The Development of Time Concepts in African Children of Primary School Age. Institute of Education University College Ibadan. Ibadan University Press. Nigeria. Occasional Publication No. 3., October1962 (Reel 16)
  - Umo, R. Kanu. Local Land Tenure and Disputes. Language Academy Editorial Bureau, Umuahia, Silent Prayer Home Press, Aba., 1949 (Reel 12)
  - Umo, R. Kanu. History of Aro Settlements. Mbonu Ojike, Yaba., undated (Reel 12)
  - Utchaey, T.K. Improved Igbo Orthography. Education Mission Press, Aba., undated (Reel 12)
  - Utchaey, T.K. The Problems of Igbo Orthography. Bookman Bookshop, Aba., undated (Reel 12)
  - Utchaey, T.K. Umuahia Today. Information Series. The Language Academy, Umuahia. No. 1., 1953 (Reel 16)
  - Utchaey, T.K. Slave Markets in East Nigeria. Information Series. Language Academy, Umuahia National Printing Works, Umuahia. No.2., undated (Reel 12)
  - Utchaey, T.K. Umuahia Today. Information Series. [note: same number as above but different publication]. The Language Academy, Umuahia." No. 2., 1955 (Reel 12)
  - Ward Price, H.L. Land Tenure in the Yoruba Provinces. Government Printer, Lagos., 1939 (Reel 12)
  - Wolff, Hans. Nigerian Orthography. North Regional Adult Education Office Gaskiya Corporation, Zaria., 1954 (Reel 12)
- Politics and social change, 1920-1969, undated (bulk 1940-1965). (Reel 12-15, 17-18)
  127 items. Arranged alphabetically by author in two groups, Aba Community League to Nigeria (reels 12-15) and Nigeria to Wali (reels 17-18).
  - Key: Title. Publisher. Author. Issue No.[when known]. Publication date.
  - Aba Community League. Local Government Reform. Criticisms and Recommendations. The Secretariat, Aba Community League, Aba., undated (Reel 12)
  - Abakaliki Co-Operative Rice Mill Society limited, Abakaliki. Bye-Laws of the Abakaliki Co-Operative Rice Mill Society Limited, Abakaliki, 1955. Bak’s Bookshop and Printing Press, Abakaliki. (Reel 12)
  - " Achogbuo, Onogbo. Iva Valley Tragedy. Continental Press, Enugu., undated (Reel 12)
  - Afikpo Town Welfare Association Constitution. Macgregor College Printing Press., 1952 (Reel 12)
  - Afikpo Town Welfare Association. Minutes of the 1st Annual Convention… Aman Press, Aba., 1951 (Reel 12)
  - Afikpo Town Welfare Association. Minutes of the Second Annual Convention of the Afikpo Town Welfare Association… Macgregor College Printing Press, Afikpo., 1952 (Reel 12)
  - Afikpo Youth Welfare League. Constitution of the Afikpo Youth Welfare League. Henshaw Press, Calabar., circa 1947 (Reel 12)
  - Agbu, Chike. I am an Ex-Prisoner. West African Pilot, Yaba., undated (Reel 13)
  - Agwuna, O.C. Inside Africa (A Study of the Colour Bar Problem). Zik’s Press Limited., 1947 (Reel 13)
  - Ajayi, G.B. (1) Industrial Development in West Africa. Economic Research Bureau, Ibadan., 1969 (Reel 13)
  - Ajibola, J.O. Economic Development of West Africa. West African Society, London., 1949 (Reel 13)
  - Akintoye, O.A. Self Government for Nigeria. O.A. Okintoye, Lagos., 1955 (Reel 13)
  - Akinyede, G.B.A. The Political and Constitutional Problems of Nigeria. Nigerian Printing and Publishing Company Ltd. Lagos., 1957 (Reel 13)
  - Anon. Native Court Handbook. 3rd impression C.M.S. (Nigeria) Press, Port Harcourt., 1956 (Reel 13)
  - Anon. Preamble and Regulations of the Diocese on the Niger, Approved 18th May 1955. C.M.S. (Nigeria) Press, Port Harcourt., undated (Reel 13)
  - Anon. The Work of the National Military Government of the Republic of Nigeria, Headed by Major-General J.T.U. Aguiyi Ironsi and his Four Military Governors. Institute of Nigeria Publicity, Onitsha., undated (Reel 13)
  - Anon. Nigeria’s Military Government. First 100 Days. Daily Times of Nigeria, Ltd., Lagos., 1966 (Reel 13)
  - Anon. The Catholic Church in an Independent Nigeria. Joint Pastoral Letter of the Nigerian Hierarchy. Claverianum Press, Ibadan., 1960 (Reel 13)
  - Anon. The “Outlook” Constitutional Supplement and Guide to Your Eastern Ministers and Legislators. The “Outlook,” Enugu., September1952 (Reel 13)
  - Anon. Who’s Who in Nigeria, A Biographical Dictionary. Nigerian Printing and Publishing Company, Lagos., 1956 (Reel 13)
  - Anon. The Independent Nigeria. Pacific Printers, Yaba., October1960 (Reel 13)
  - Anon. The Organisation of Procedure of Local Government Councils. C.M.S. (Nigeria) Press, Port Harcourt., undated (Reel 13)
  - Anon. Outward Bound to the New Nigeria. Man O’War Bay Training Centre. Edward G. Dunstan Co., London., circa 1959 (Reel 13)
  - Anunobi, Nlewedim. How Shall We Help? Zik’s Press Ltd., Lagos., 1950 (Reel 14)
  - Anyiam, Frederick Uzoma. Among Nigerian Celebrities. Sankey Printing Works, Yaba., 1960 (Reel 14)
  - Anyiam, Frederick Uzoma. Men and Matters in Nigerian Politics, 1934-58. John Okwesa and Co., Yaba., 1959 (Reel 14)
  - Aririguzo, Cyril N. Steps for the Freedom of Nigeria. Eastern Niger Printing Press, Onitsha., undated (Reel 14)
  - Armstrong, R.G. The Issues at Stake, Nigeria, 1967. Ibadan University Press. (Reel 14)
  - Azikiwe, Nnamdi. The Evolution of Federal Government in Nigeria. Freedom Printing Press, Orlu., circa 1955 (Reel 14)
  - Azikiwe, Nnamdi. Choose Independence in 1960 or More States. A National Challenge. Varsity Publishing Co., Onitsha., undated (Reel 14)
  - Azikiwe, Nnamdi. Nigeria in World Politics. Office of the Commissioner for the Eastern Region of Nigeria in the United Kingdom, London., 1959 (Reel 14)
  - Azikiwe, Nnamdi. Taxation in Nigeria. African Book Company, Ltd. Lagos., 1943 (Reel 14)
  - Azikiwe, Nnamdi. Spiritual Rebirth for Africa. Moral Re-Armament, London., 1952 (Reel 14)
  - Azikiwe, Nnamdi. Economic Reconstruction of Nigeria. African Book Company, Lagos., 1943 (Reel 14)
  - Azikiwe, Nnamdi. The Development of Political Parties in Nigeria. Office of the Commissioner in the United Kingdom for the Eastern Region of Nigeria, London., August 1957 (Reel 14)
  - Azikiwe, Nnamdi. Renascent Africa. The Author, Lagos., undated (Reel 14)
  - Azikiwe, Nnamdi. Respect for Human Dignity, An Inaugural Address Delivered by His Excellency Dr. Nnamdi. Azikiwe, Governor-General and Commander-in-Chief, Federation of Nigeria, 16 November 1960. Government Printer, Enugu., undated (Reel 14)
  - Balogun, Kola. As Youth Sees It. Zik's Press, Ltd., Lagos., 1947 (Reel 14)
  - Balogun, Kola. What Nigeria Wants. Chuks, Lagos., undated (Reel 14)
  - Balogun, Kola. Home Rule Now! Obajinmi Printing Works, Lagos., undated (Reel 14)
  - Balogun, Kola. My Country, Nigeria! Sankey Printing Works, Yaba., 1955 (Reel 14)
  - Berrie, G.K., Fielstra, C., et al. University of Lagos. The Truth About the Change in Vice-Chancellorship. The Authors, Yaba., 1965 (Reel 14)
  - Chadwick, E.R. Our Community Effort in the East. Crownbird Series, No. 30 (Special). Public Relations Department, Lagos. A Crownbird Special., undated (Reel 14)
  - Chukwuemeka, Nwankwo. Industrialization of Nigeria. William-Frederick Press, New York., 1951 (Reel 14)
  - Chukwuemeka, Okonkwo. The Unity of Nigeria. Sankey Press, Yaba [Author signs himself Chukwuemeka Okonkwo Ojoto in his Introduction]., 1952 (Reel 14)
  - Coker, E.O. The Eternal Sacred Order of Cherubim and Seraphim. ""The Order."" Dek's Press, Enugu., undated (Reel 14)
  - Coker, Increase. Seventy Years of the Nigerian Press. A 'Daily Times' Publication., undated (Reel 14)
  - Delano, Isaac O. Notes and Comments from Nigeria. Africa's Own Library. United Society for Christian Literature (Lutterworth Press), London. No.8, undated (Reel 14)
  - Dikko, Alhaji Muhammadu. Sarkin Katsina, 1865-1944. Gaskiya Corporation, Zaria., 1951 (Reel 14)
  - Eguoritse, Prince O. Feathers for a Great Nigerian Statesman. Being a Short Biographical Portrait of Chief the Hon. F.S. Okotie-Eboh. Twentieth Century Press, Ebute Metta., circa 1959 (Reel 14)
  - Ejimofor, Emeribe. You and Your Troubled World. Education Mission Press, Aba., 1952 (Reel 14)
  - Elias, T.O. Federation vs. Confederation and the Nigerian Federation. Government of Trinidad and Tobago, Port-of-Spain, Trinidad., 1960 (Reel 14)
  - Enahoro, Anthony. Nnamdi. Azikiwe: Saint or Sinner? Ribway Press, Lagos., undated (Reel 15)
  - Enahoro, Peter. How to be a Nigerian. Daily Times of Nigeria, Lagos., 1966 (Reel 15)
  - Great Britain. Colonial Office. Enquiry into the Cost of Living and the Control of the Cost of Living in the Colony and Protectorate of Nigeria. London: H.M.S.O. Colonial. No. 204., 1946 (Reel 15)
  - Great Britain. Colonial Office. Report of the Commission of Enquiry into the Disorders in the Eastern Provinces of Nigeria, November, 1949. London: H.M.S.O. Colonial. No. 257., 1950 (Reel 15)
  - Great Britain. Colonial Office. Report of the Commission of Enquiry into the Disorders in the Eastern Provinces of Nigeria, November, 1949. London: H.M.S.O. Colonial. No. 256., 1950 (Reel 15)
  - Hennessy, Maurice. Our Marketing Boards. Crownbird Series. Marketing Publicity Section, Public Relations Department, Lagos. No.2., undated (Reel 15)
  - Ibo State Union. Constitution Amac's Press, Port Harcourt., undated (Reel 15)
  - Ibo State Union. The Ibo State Union Memorandum to the Willink's Minorities Commission. Nigerian Popular Printing Press and Bookshops, Port Harcourt., undated (Reel 15)
  - The Igbobian. The Chronical of Igbobi College, Lagos, December, 1958. John Okwesa and Co., Yaba., undated (Reel 15)
  - Ibuoro, SON. Our Country, Nigeria. Goodwill Printing Press, Port Harcourt., 1954 (Reel 15)
  - Ikoku, Chimere. Science Education in the United States. A Guide to Prospective Students. Pacific Printing and Publishing Works, Lagos., undated (Reel 15)
  - Ilogu, Edmund. Social Pholosphy for the New Nigeria Nation. Etudo Limited, Onitsha., undated (Reel 15)
  - Jokparoba, R.E. The Urhobo People in Nigerian Politics. Obajinmi Printing Works, Lagos., circa 1958 (Reel 15)
  - Juwe, S.M. Why is The National Church of Nigeria and the Cameroons and the God of Africa. Goodwill Press, Port Harcourt., undated (Reel 15)
  - Juwe, S.M. Zik and the Freedom of Nigeria. Goodwill Press, Port Harcourt., 1953 (Reel 15)
  - Juwe, S.M. Zik in London. Goodwill Press, Port Harcourt., 1953 (Reel 15)
  - ""Lash"" [Pseud. for Akinola Lasekan] Zik of Africa. Zik's Press, Ltd. Lagos., 1947 (Reel 15)
  - Lugard, F.D. Nigeria. Report by Sir F.D. Lugard on the Amalgamation of Northern and Southern Nigeria, and Administration, 1912-1919. London. H.M.S.O. Cmd. 468., 1920 (Reel 15)
  - Mba, Peter U. What is a Constitution? Henshaw Press, Calabar., 1949 (Reel 15)
  - Mbadiwe, George Igbodebe. Golden Dawn. Ife-Olu Printing Works, Lagos., 1947 (Reel 15)
  - Mbah, A.N. The Life Story of Zik. Providence Printing Press, Onitsha., undated (Reel 15)
  - Mgbako, Fanasi. Truth and Falsehood. Addresses of Welcome Presented to Dr. K.O. Mbadiwe and Dr. Nnamdi. Azikiwe. New Era Press, Onitsha., undated (Reel 15)
  - Morton-Williams, P. Cinema in Rural Nigeria. A Field Study of the Impact of Fundamental-Education Films on Rural Audiences in Nigeria. Federal Information Services. Gaskiya Corporation, Zaria., undated (Reel 15)
  - Ndem, Eyo B.E. Ibos in Contemporary Nigerian Politics, A Study in Group Conflict. Etudo Limited, Onitsha., 1961 (Reel 15)
  - Nicol, B.M. Feeding Nigeria. Federal Information Service Publication. Government Printer, Lagos., undated (Reel 17)
  - Nigeria. Report of the Parliamentary Delegation to Fernando Po and Rio Muni, 1957. Government Printer, Lagos. (Reel 15)
  - Nigeria. Report on Employment of Nigerian Labour in Fernando Poo, Sessional Paper No. 38, of 1939. Legislative council. Government Printer, Lagos. No.38. (Reel 15)
  - Nigeria. Agricultural Department. Eastern Provinces. Rice Cultivation in the Eastern Provinces. Enugu., undated (Reel 17)
  - Nigeria Church Union Committee. The Constitution of the Church of Nigeria. Abiodun Printing Works, Ibadan., 1965 (Reel 17)
  - Nigerian Socialist Group. Nigeria for Socialism. Continental Press, Enugu., circa 1960 (Reel 17)
  - Nzewi, J. Ndubizu. New Trends in Nigerian Education. Delta Printing Press, Aba., 1955 (Reel 17)
  - Obanu, Daniel Ikechi. The Nigerian Citizen and Personality Drama. Ofomatas Press, Aba., undated (Reel 17)
  - Obi, Chike. I Speak for the People. Department of Propaganda and Spiritual Education Ibadan., 1960 (Reel 17)
  - Ogbalu, F. Chidozie. Dr. Zik of Africa; Biography and Speeches. Varsity Bookshop, Onitsha., undated (Reel 17)
  - Oduntan, O. Just Before the 1950 Reforms, by a Political Umpire. Ibadan., 1949 (Reel 17)
  - Ofokansi, Chuma. Has Zik Any Political Ambition? Anno Printing Press, Enugu., undated (Reel 17)
  - Ohiaeri, N. Ekpe Ibe. Nationalism and African Education, The Road to Success. Tabansi Printing Press, Onitsha., 1957 (Reel 17)
  - Ohiaeri, N. Ekpe Ibe. University Education in Nigeria. Etukokwu and Sons Press., 1957 (Reel 17)
  - Ohiaeri, N. Ekpe Ibe. Our Greater ""Lux Fiat."" Tabansi Printing Press, Onitsha., 1957 (Reel 17)
  - Ohonbamu, Obarogie. Nigeria: The Army and the People's Cause. African Education Press, Ibadan., 1966 (Reel 17)
  - Ojike, Mbonu. The Road to Freedom. Henshaw Press, Calabar., undated (Reel 17)
  - Okafor, Amanke. Nigeria. Why We Fight for Freedom. Farleigh Press Ltd., Watford, Herts, England. 3rd edition, 1950 (Reel 17)
  - Okorafor, Charles N. The United Nations Student Association in Nigeria. Assumpta Press, Owerri., 1959 (Reel 17)
  - Okoye, Mokwugo. The Rebel Line. Etudo Limited, Onitsha., 1962 (Reel 17)
  - Olugboji, Dayo. The Problem of Nigerian Overseas Students. C.M.S. (Nigeria) Press, Lagos., 1959 (Reel 17)
  - Omoregie, Samuel O. A Glance at Benin Politics. Central Press Ltd., Sapele., 1952 (Reel 17)
  - Onyechi, Ogojofo. An Approach to the Nigerian Problem. Mbidokwu's Press, Onitsha., 1949 (Reel 18)
  - Onyido, Udemezue. The N.C.N.C. Delegation to London of 1947. Education Mission Press, Aba., 1949 (Reel 18)
  - Onyioha, K.O.K. Revival of Culture in Independent Nigeria. Eastern Nigeria Printing Corporation, Enugu., 1962 (Reel 18)
  - Opara, E.O. Co-Operation and Conflict. Education Mission Press, Aba., 1950 (Reel 18)
  - Oresanya, A.O. An Outline of The System of Administration in Nigeria. Ife-Olu Printing Works, Lagos., 1942 (Reel 18)
  - Orizu, Okwudili. To Rule is a Trouble. Book 1. Providence Printing Press, Onitsha., undated (Reel 18)
  - Radley, T.B. Our Revised Constitution. Crownbird Series, Nigerian Information Service, Lagos, Crownbird Publication No.38 (Special), 1954 (Reel 18)
  - Solarin, Tai. Towards Nigeria's Moral Self-Government. The Author, Ikenne., 1959 (Reel 18)
  - Stocker, John. Legislative Coucil at Work. August Meeting, 1948. Public Relations Officer, Nigeria. Lagos. (Reel 18)
  - Tokunboh, M.A. A Simple Guide for African Trade Unions. Nigerian Printing and Publishing Co., Lagos., undated (Reel 18)
  - Udokwu, Chuba. The Nigerian and American Education. Olugbadewa Printing Press, Lagos., 1952 (Reel 18)
  - Umo, R. Kanu. Blue Subjectives. Language Academy Editorial Bureau. Umuahia, S.P.H. Press, Aba., 1947 (Reel 18)
  - Utchay, T.K. Principles and Methods of Right Thinking. Knodubi Philosophy. Book I. Education Mission Press, Aba., 1952 (Reel 18)
  - Utchay, T.K. The African Universal Church and Commercial League Corporation Prayer and Hymn Book. Education Mission Press, Aba., 1951 (Reel 18)
  - Utchay, T.K. Missionary Photographs. No. 1. Education Missionary Society, Port Harcourt., undated (Reel 18)
  - Utchay, T.K. A Letter to the Eastern House of Assembly. Education Mission Press, Aba., circa 1951 (Reel 18)
  - Utchay, T.K. Governments Reply to the Arochuku People. Education Mission Society, Aba., circa 1950 (Reel 18)
  - Utchay, T.K. A Letter to the Elders of Arochuku. Education Mission Society, Aba., 1951 (Reel 18)
  - Utchay, T.K. Constitution and Rules. Education Missionary Society, Port Harcourt., undated (Reel 18)
  - Utchay, T.K. Co-Operation in Practice. An Appeal to the Education Department Through the Governor in Council. Education Mission, Aba., 1951 (Reel 18)
  - Utchay, T.K. A Message to the Honourable Members, with Copy to the Common Man Education Missionary Society, Port Harcourt., circa 1950 (Reel 18)
  - Utchay, T.K. My Defence in 1946. Education Missionary Society, Port Harcourt. Document No. 7. 2nd edition., undated (Reel 18)
  - Utchay, T.K. I said to Myself. Education Mission Press, Aba., 1942 (Reel 18)
  - Utchay, T.K. A Good Beginning. Education Missionary Society, Port Harcourt., 1948 (Reel 18)
  - Utchay, T.K. National Hymns and Prayers for Use in the National Church of Nigeria and the Cameroons. National Church of Nigeria and the Cameroons, Aba., undated (Reel 18)
  - Uwadiegwu, C.O. The Complete Story and Works of Military Government and Nigerian Current Affairs Past and Present. n.p., undated (Reel 18)
  - Uwanaka, Charles U. Zik and Awolowo in Political Storm Pacific Printing and Publishing Works, Lagos. 4th edition., undated (Reel 18)
  - Uzo, T.M. The Nigerian Political Evolution Olympian Publishing Bureau. Ife-Olu Printing Works, Lagos (circa 1949)., undated (Reel 18)
  - Wali, O. Chiefs of the Eastern Region of Nigeria African Authors' Association of Nigeria Gaskiya Corporation, Zaria., undated (Reel 18)